In this lesson, we'll introduce lane
chain expression language, or LCEL.
This is a new syntax that makes it much
easier, and more transparent to construct,
Let's get to it.
A lot of the power of
Langchain comes from composing
And we have a new way of doing this,
and this is LCEL and a runnable
protocol which define a few things.
First, it defines an
allowed set of input types,
There's then a bunch of standard
methods, and we'll go over all of these,
There are ways of
modifying parameters at runtime,
What is this interface that we
expect all runnables to expose?
First, there are a few
common methods there's
There's invoke, which calls the
runnable on a single input. There's stream,
which calls it on a single
input in stream's backer response.
And then, there's batch which
calls it on a list of inputs.
For all of these synchronous methods,
there's also a corresponding async method.
There's common properties
that all runnables have,
namely an input schema
and an output schema.
And you can see a list of the input and
output types for common components below.
Why use LCL?
There are a few
benefits that this gets you.
First, you get async batch and
streaming support out of the box.
Second, a big part of
working with LLMs is that
they're a little bit
unpredictable sometimes.
They don't always respond
how you want them to respond.
And so, you can easily attach fallbacks
not only to LLMs but also to entire chains.
Third, parallelism. LLM
calls can be time-consuming.
They often take a while
and so it's really important
to run them in parallel if you can.
And the LCEL syntax
makes it easy to do that.
And fourth, logging is built in.
As these chains and agents
get more and more complex,
being able to see the
sequence of steps and the inputs and
outputs becomes crucial for
building an LLM application.
And we've added things into the
open source library. And then,
And LCAL natively logs
all of these things,
With that, it's time to get to the code
and see what this actually looks like.
First, let's set up our
environment as before.
We'll then import a few different
components that we're going to compose together.
First, we'll import a prompt template.
Next, we'll import a language
model, and we'll be using OpenAI.
And finally, we'll
import an output parser,
Let's now use these
components to create a simple chain
of prompt template to
language model to output parser.
So first, let's create a prompt template.
And we'll create one that asks the
language model to tell us a short joke.
We'll then initialize the language
model that we're going to use and
finally we'll create the output
parser that we're going to use.
And we can now call this chain
using the invoke method on some inputs.
And the inputs here are going to be
the inputs to the prompt template. So,
And so, if we call this, we
can see we get back a joke.
Why don't bears ever
get caught in traffic?
Because they always take
the beariest best routes.
Now's a good time to pause a little bit,
pass in some other arguments to this
function, maybe change up the prompt,
play around with it, and get a
sense for these different components,
We'll now create a
slightly more complex chain.
In the previous short course, we went
over how to do retrieval augmented generation.
And so, we'll replicate that same
process using link chain expression language.
First, we need to set up our retriever.
We're first going to create a
really simple vector store.
We're going to do this by
initializing it with two texts. First,
Harrison worked at Kensho. And next,
bears like to eat honey well. Then,
If we call it on something different, if
we call it on what do bears like to eat,
we can see that the first result that
we get back is bears like to eat honey.
In order to create this pipeline,
we're first going to create a
prompt that basically asks the language
model to answer the question
based only on the following context.
And it has two variables here.
It has context and question.
And so, we're going to
be passing in two things.
And then, we're going to
be passing in the context.
We want the first and only input to the
chain to be the user question. From then,
we want to fetch relevant context. And
then, we want to pass that into the prompt.
To do that, we're going to use a
runnable map which we can import this way.
We want this runnable
map to have two elements.
We can write a lambda function that
calls retriever.getRelevantDocuments
and passes in the question parameter.
We also want to pass along the
original question parameter,
From here, we want to pass
it into the prompt. And then,
We can then name this as our
chain, and we now have a new runnable.
And now, if we invoke this with a
question, like where did Harrison work,
If we want to take a closer look at
what exactly is going on under the scenes,
we can just look at this
runnable map directly.
And then, if we just run this
on the same thing. And then,
This is then getting passed into the
prompt which is then creating a prompt
One of the other
things that we can do with
runnables is we can
bind parameters to them.
And so normally, this would look
like a prompt. And then, a model.
But where do the functions go in? And so,
And what this will do under the
hood is that when the model is called
it will pass any parameters in
bind along to the invocation.
So now, if we create a runnable by
doing prompt and then pipe model,
If you wanted to change that
you would just overwrite it.
And now, we have these two
different functions here.
We can just update the model by
binding it with new functions.
And then, when we call this new
runnable which we're using the new model in,
One of the really powerful
things about language and expression
language is you can
easily attach fallbacks,
not only to individual
components, but to entire sequences.
In order to create a situation
where this is going to fail,
we'll actually use an
older version of a language
model from OpenAI that
isn't quite as good.
To do that, we're going to import an
OpenAI language model from lanechain.llms.
This is different than the chat models.
The chat models are newer
types of models and so they're
generally pretty good at
things like outputting JSON,
but older models which is
lanechain.llms, generally aren't.
We'll now create a simple
model and a simple chain.
In this simple model we're going to be
setting temperature equals zero. So,
Our chain is just going to
be calling this language
model and then piping the
result into JSON.loads.
This will break if the result of
the language model isn't valid JSON.
Let's now create a challenge
problem statement for the language model.
We're going to ask it to
write three poems in a JSON
blob where each poem is
a JSON blob of a title,
author, and the first line.
This is a pretty challenging problem
and we want it to respond in valid JSON.
And so, if we run the
simple model on this,
But if we take this and we
try to decode it with JSON,
we can see that we get a JSON
decode error because of what
that model is outputting
isn't actually valid JSON.
The new models from OpenAI are
pretty good at outputting valid JSON.
And then, we're going to pipe
that string into JSON.loads.
If we use the same
challenge with this model,
we can see that it
correctly outsplits valid JSON.
In order to use fallbacks, what we
can do is we can create a final chain,
and we can start with the
simple chain. And then,
In with fallbacks we'll pass
in a list of other runnables,
If an error is raised, then it
goes through this list in order.
If we now call this
chain on the challenge,
we can see that it
responds in the correct format.
Finally, let's talk about the
interface that these runnables expose.
Let's go back to the
chain that we had before.
We're asking it to tell us a joke.
And let's take a look at a few
different elements of this interface.
The one that we were using
from the get-go is invoke.
This is a synchronous method
that calls it on one input.
There's also batch which is going
to call it on a list of inputs.
So here, we pass in two
different inputs, one with
And under the hood this is actually
executing them in parallel as much as possible.
We can also stream back responses.
And finally, all of these methods
have corresponding asynchronous methods.
That is it for this lesson,
but there's a lot of different ways
that you can combine all these elements
and put together really
complicated types of chains and sequences.
We sometimes see sequences that get
up to 300 or 400 components in a row.
And so, before moving on,
Can you do two, three, even four
language model calls in a row?
What does that look like?
Lots of fun things to explore.
In the next lesson, we're going to
combine what we just learned here,
language and expression
language, with what we covered
in the previous lesson,
open AI function calls.
And we're going to show how to
use those two things together.